University of Arizona Office of the President records, 1914-1937
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Office of the President records, 1914-1937
AZ 420
The University of Arizona Office of the President records consist of correspondence and financial papers relating to administration and management of areas such as building and grounds, faculty and student issues, military and R.O.T.C., land acquisitions, academic departments, requests for information, Federal relief programs of 1932-1937, external agencies and organizations, and other issues.
University of Arizona. Office of the President
11.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Organization
This collection is organized into five series:
Series I. R.B. von KleinSmid and Frank C. Lockwood Papers, 1914-1922
Series II. Cloyd H. Marvin Papers, 1922-1927
Series III. Byron Cummings Papers, 1927-1928
Series IV. Homer L. Shantz Papers, 1928-1936
Series V. Paul S. Burgess Papers, 1936-1937
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence and financial papers relating to administration and management of areas such as building and grounds, faculty and student issues, military and R.O.T.C., land acquisitions, academic departments, requests for information, Federal relief programs of 1932-1937, external agencies and organizations, and other issues. Correspondents include Governors George W.P. Hunt, John C. Phillips, and Benjamin B. Moeur; various Board of Regents members, U.S. Veteran's Bureau, Arizona Historical Society, Arizona State Legislature, University faculty members, and others. Includes professional activity files of Homer L. Shantz.
KleinSmid, Rufus Bernhard von, 1875-1964; Lockwood, Frank C. (Frank Cummins), 1864-1948; Greenway, Isabella; Hayden, Carl Trumbull, 1877-1972 -- Correspondence; Marvin, Cloyd Heck, 1889-1969; Cummings, Byron, 1860-1954; Shantz, H. L. (Homer LeRoy), 1876-1958; Burgess, Paul, 1886-1958; Hunt, George W. P. (George Wylie Paul), 1859-1934 -- Correspondence; Phillips, John C. -- Correspondence; Moeur, Benjamin -- Correspondence; Arizona Historical Society; Arizona. Legislature; University of Arizona -- Faculty; University of Arizona -- Records and correspondence; Arizona Board of Regents; University of Arizona -- History; Depressions -- 1929 -- Arizona; Arizona -- History -- Sources; Correspondence
Related Material
Additional President's papers at AZ 76, AZ 406, AZ 426, AZ 427.
Container List
- Series I: R.B. von KleinSmid and Cloyd H. Lockwood Papers, 1914-1922
  - R.B. von KleinSmid miscellaneous correspondence, includes the Proposed Plan of Administration for the University of Arizona, as adopted by the Faculty, October 1, 1920. 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid miscellaneous correspondence, includes the Proposed Plan of Administration for the University of Arizona, as adopted by the Faculty, October 1, 1920. 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid miscellaneous financial papers, most refer to Agricultural Extension work. 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid materials regarding Students Army Training Corps, includes material on the local flu epidemic, and the use of University facilities. 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid materials regarding subscriptions from mining companies for the Mines and Engineering Building. 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid materials regarding the establishment of Post Office in "Old Main". 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid materials regarding the Federal Board for Vocational Education. 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid materials regarding the Yuma Experiment Station fence controversy. 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - R.B. von KleinSmid, Brochures for Forest Laun Memorial Park, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Frank C. Lockwood correspondence with former President von KleinSmid. 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Frank C. Lockwood miscellaneous correspondence. 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Frank C. Lockwood miscellaneous financial papers. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Frank C. Lockwood materials regarding buildings and grounds, includes fire escapes and street improvements. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Frank C. Lockwood materials regarding poultry projects. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Frank C. Lockwood materials regarding Veterans' Bureau. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Frank C. Lockwood statistical material for the U.S. Bureau of Education Survey Committee, published as Report of a Survey of the University of Arizona. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II: Cloyd H. Marvin Papers, 1922-1927
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1924-1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Questionnaires. 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Athletic Questionaires. 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Requests for Information: Salaries, Marble Quarries in Arizona. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Correspondence. 1922-1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - President Marvin's reorganization of faculty. October 1922 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Faculty: Marguerite Marrow, Drama. 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Faculty: Charles F. Rogers, Music. 1924-1926 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Faculty: Dean of Women, forms used. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Committees. 1922-1927 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Publications. 1922-1927 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Department of Health Administration: Includes infirmary reports, fees and financial records, lists of consulting physicians, etc. 1923-1926 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Department of Law Reports and Syllabi. 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Department of Physics. 1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous student correspondence. 1922-1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Students: Death of Paul Long. 1923 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Students: Wilma Kavanaugh Case. 1925 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Registrar reports, statistics, etc. 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Papers. 1923-1927 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes material regarding the paving of Second Street, faculty salary scales, literary lecture series, dining hall report, Experiment Station work, improvements on University grounds, and a Taxpayer Committee's complaint about the University's expenditures.
  - Ruling of the Attorney General. 1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Proposed separate College of Agriculture. 1923 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Athletic Board Control. 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Land sale of the Experiment Station Farm, Cochise County. 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Various land transactions. 1922-1926 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Library Building: Snead & Co. 1923-1926 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Library Building decoration and furniture. 1926 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Military and R.O.T.C., including Polo. 1923-1927 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Munk Library. 1921-1926 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Veterans' Bureau. 1924-1927 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - American Association of University Women. 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Association of Governing Boards of State Universities and Allied Institutions. 1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Association of Land Grant Colleges. 1923-1927 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Arizona State Statistics. 1922-1927 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous material. 1919-1926 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Material includes more on the Plan of Administration of the University; Doctors' Academy meeting minutes, December 1923; Graphical Interpretation of County Agent Work, 1919-1922; the "Y" Hut; Debate schedule, 1926; and the lease between Louise Marshall & husband and the Board of Regents for the Post Office in building on University Ave., 1923.
  - Miscellaneous reports from the Agricultural Extension Service and the Agricultural Experiment Station. 1922-1925 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Series III: Byron Cummings Papers, 1927-1928
  - Board of Regents. 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Governor G. W. P. Hunt. February 1927-June 1928 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Faculty: G.M Butler, Dean of College of Mines and Engineering and Director of Arizona Bureau of Mines. 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Faculty: J.F. McKale, Physical Education for men. 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Faculty: Charles F. Rogers, Director of the School of Music. 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Faculty: J.J. Thornber, Dean of the College of Agriculture and Director of the Agricultural Station. 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Faculty: High School visitor reports. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Committees. 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous faculty correspondence. 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence. February 1927-June 1928 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Requests for information, etc. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Complaints 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Students, miscellaneous. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Students: Injury of James A Rork. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Students: Marjorie Akers Case, course work for degree. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Advertising and Publicity. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Buffalo for the State Museum, includes correspondence with Gov. Hunt. 1927 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Buildings and Grounds, Dining hall improvements. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Building and Grounds, Heating plant. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Buildings and Grounds, Library and Gymnasium. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous financial papers. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Financial Papers in regards to the Marvin Entertainment Fund. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Graduate College controversy. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Infirmary and Student Health. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Insurance. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Land purchase of Forbes property on Olive Road. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Lead Crosses. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Mexican Affairs. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Military and R.O.T.C., including correspondence Re: new riding corral. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Radio Commission. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - University Press proposal. 1927 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - State Department of Vocational Education. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Veterans' Bureau. 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Series IV: Homer L. Shantz Papers, 1928-1936
  - Board of Regents and Governors, 1927-1936
    - F.J. Crider. 1927-1935 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Robert E. Tally. 1927-1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Robert E. Tally. 1927-1936 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - H.S. McCluskey. 1928-1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - William C. Joyner. 1929-1931 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - A.M. Crawford. 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Various. 1927-1936 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Meeting minutes, "off the record", drafts only and notes by HLS. 1931-1935 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Governor George W.P. Hunt. 1928 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Governor John C. Phillips. 1920-1929 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Governor George P. Hunt. 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Governor Benjamin B. Moeur. 1932-1936 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Arizona State Officials, 1928-1937
    - Arizona State Legislature. 1929-1935 (Box 6a, Folder 1)
    - Arizona State Legislature. 1929-1935 (Box 6a, Folder 2)
    - A.M. Crawford, Legislative Examiner. 1930-1932 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
    - Thank you letters from State Legislators for football tickets. 1934-1935 (Box 6a, Folder 4)
    - Rulings of the Attorney General. 1928-1937 (Box 6a, Folder 5)
  - Faculty A-Z, 1928-1936
    - Anderson, Arthur Olaf. Dean of the College of Fine Arts. Includes material regarding University Artist and Lecture Series. 1935-1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Ernest. Chemistry. 1930-1936 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Bachman, Albert. French. 1930-1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Ball, E.D. Dean of the College of Agriculture; Director of Agricultural Experiment Station; Economic Zoology. 1928-1936 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ballantyne, A.B. Rural Sociology. 1933-1936 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Boggs, Edward M. Civil Engineering (1892-1897) Regarding gift of his library to the University. 1932 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Breazeale, James F. Reseach Biochemistry, U.S.D.A. Includes information about the beginnings of the Boyce Thompson Southwestern Arboretum. 1927-1932 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Brown, Elmer J. Economics and Business. 1929-1934 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Brown J.G. Plant Pathology. 1928-1931 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Burgess, Paul S. Agricultural Chemist; Dean of the College of Agriculture; Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station. 1928-1937,1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Butler, G. M. Dean of the College of Mines & Engineering; Director of the Arizona Bureau of Mines. 1928-1936,1946 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cable, W. Arthur. Speech. 1930-1935 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Carpenter, Edwin F. Astronomy and Steward Observatory. Includes the "city lights" program. 1931-1936 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Clarson, J.W. Jr. Dean of the College of Education. 1929-1935 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Cummings, Byron. Archaeology and State Museum. 1927-1935 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Douglass, Andrew Ellicott. Astronomy and Tree Rings. 1928-1934 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Fancett, George. Mines. Mostly regarding Extension Lectures. 1928-1933 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Fegtly, Samuel M. Dean of the College of Law. 1929-1936 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Fitz-Gerald, John D. Spanish. Includes Pan American Day Celebration, April 14, 1931. 1929-1938 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Gittings, Ina E. Physical Education for Women. 1929-1936 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Gjelsness, Rodolph H. Library. 1933-1935 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Johnson, B. Eleanor. Home Economics 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Jones, Evelyn W. Dean of Women. 1929-1936 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Lesher, C. Zaner. Registrar. Includes registration statistics. 1928-1937 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Life, Frank M. Physics. 1927-1933 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Lockwood, Frank C. Dean of the College of Letters, Arts, Sciences; English. 1928-1936 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Lutrell, Estelle. Library. 1928-1935 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Mckale, J.F. Physical Education for Men. 1928-1935 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Mather, Stella. Home Economics. 1928-1931 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Mathewson, Edward P. Mining and Metallurgy. Includes special fund-rasing activities. 1927-1937 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Marrow, Marguerite. Drama. 1927-1936 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Nichol, A.A. Botany and Range Ecology. Includes letters from Myrilla (Walcutt) Nichol. 1935-1942 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Pattison, Sidney F. English. 1927-1936 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Pease, Rollin. Music. 1931-1942? (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Riesen, E.R. Philosophy; Dean of the College of Letters, Arts and Sciences. 1928-1936 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Rogers, Charles F. Music. 1928-1935 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Ross, Pontus H. Director of the Agricultural Extension Service. 1928-1936 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Smith, G.E.P. Irrigation Engineering. 1928-1935 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Margaret C. Nutrition. 1931-1933 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Howard V. Agricultural Chemistry. 1931-1933 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Thomas, F.E. Law. 1930-1935 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Thornber, J.J. Dean of the College of Agriculture and Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station; Botany. 1927-1935 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Vorhies, Charles T. Entomology; Acting President. 1928-1933 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Walker, J. Franklin. Education. 1929-1933 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Wood, C.J. Superintendent of Agriculture Experiment Station Farm, Mesa. 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence with Faculty and Staff. 1928-1936 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence with Faculty and Staff. 1928-1936 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence with Faculty, Staff, former students and others after leaving the University of Arizona. 1936-1952 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Library Faculty Committees. 1930-1932 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Various Faculty Committees. 1928-1936 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Faculty Club. 1933-1936 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Faculty material. 1928-1936 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Salary Scales. 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Teaching Loads, University of Arizona and elsewhere. 1932-1935 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Students, 1928-1936
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence from and about Students. 1928-1936 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Student "Life and Times", see also Complaints, Box 15. 1928-1936 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Registration, Dormitory Fees, and Scholarship Standing. 1928-1936 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Residence Status. 1928-1936 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Need for work. 1928-1936 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Indian Students. 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Parents' letters: Take care of my little boy, etc. 1928-1936 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Charles Hitch, Rhodes Scholar. 1932-1935 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1927-1936
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Folders 1-7 Include letters from: Hamlin Garland regarding lectures, January 19, 1928; Neil Judd regarding proposed State Museum building on campus, May 18, 1928; Gene Tunney in reply to his HLS's offer of a position in the P.E. Department, January 4, 1934; and various individuals in reply to HLS's applications for a position somewhere in the scientific world, April 1935.
    - Atwood, Wallance W. 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Baird, Matthew. 1930-1935 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Barnes, Will C. 1934-1936 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Bumstead, Dale. 1928-1936 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Fairgrieve, Russell and Southern Arizona School for Boys. 1930-1935 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Hutchins, Robert M. 1931-1933 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - KleinSmid, Rufus B. von., (see also Box 21: Commencement, 1935). 1928-1935 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - McCormick, Ada P. 1930-1936 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Includes material regarding and from Ida Tarbell and the Conference on Biography, given at the University February-March 1931
    - Marvin, Cloyd H. 1929-1935? (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Mathews, William R. 1931-1935 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Sparkes, Grace M. 1931-1936 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Vischer, Hanns. 1929-1935 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Von Hagen, Wolfgang. 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1928-1936
    - William J. Bray and Buildings and Grounds. 1928-1937 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - William J. Bray and Buildings and Grounds. Includes speech of HLS at ground-breaking, July 22, 1935. 1928-1937 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Campus Committee. 1928-1936 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Automobiles. 1931-1935 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Opening of Entrance gates. 1930-1933 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Equipment. 1931-1936 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Mail Service. 19281935 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Stadium and Athletic Field. 1929 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Stone Wall around UA. 1932-1936 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Swimming Pool. 1928-1933 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Tennis Courts. 1929-1935 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Original notes, etc. on P.W.A. Building Program and Telegrams regarding the P.W.A. Loan. 1933-1934 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Topics, 1928-1936
    - Advertising and publicity. 1929-1935 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Agricultural Extensions. 1930-1935 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Proposed All-Arizona Summer School. 1928-1929 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Alumni. 1927-1934 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Assembly Programs. 1928-1936 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Athletics. 1929-1935 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Proposed College of Aeronautics. 1929 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Proposed College of Business Administration. 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - College of Law. 1928-1935 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Extension Division. 1928-1936 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Extension Division, Retail salesmanship classes by Mabel Cox; includes letter from Mary Pickford, April 7, 1936. 1928-1936 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Misc. Financial Records. 1928-1936 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Fine Arts: Art. 1930-1935 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Includes correspondence regarding Mrs. A. Y.Smith's paintings for the Library's Reading Room and Kate T. Cory's mural for the State Museum, 1930.
    - Fine Arts: Band and Joseph DeLuca. 1931-1936 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Fine Arts: Music, Drama and the Artist Series. Includes correspondence with the Saturday Morning Musical Club. 1929-1935 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Fraternities and Sororities. 1928-1935 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Infirmary, health problems, Injuries, etc. 1929-1936 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Insurance. 1928-1936 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Land. See also Box 22, Saguaro Cactus Forest. 1927-1936 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lectures. 1928-1936 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Lectures: Larado Taft. 1933-1934 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Legal Cases: Alma Binzel. 1933 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Legal Cases: Minimum wages. 1936 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Legal Cases: Various. 1929-1936 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Affairs. 1929-1934 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Military and R.O.T.C. Includes letters from Governor Hunt, Senators Carl Hayden and Henery F. Ashurst, and Representatives Isabella Greenway and Lewis W. Douglas. 1929-1936 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Military and R.O.T.C. Includes letters from Govenor Hunt, Senators Carl Hayden and Henery F. Ashurst, and Representatives Isabella Greenway and Lewis W. Douglas. 1929-1936 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Phi Beta Kappa. 1928-1931 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Polo. 1931-1936 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Polo: Will Rogers. 1931-1932, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Printing and Engraving. 1930-1934 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Radio Station broadcasts. Includes KVOA's proposal to move its transmitter to the campus, 1936. 1928-1936 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Scholarships: Heard. 1929-1936 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Scholarships: Various. 1928-1936 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Proposed School of Pharmacy. 1930-1931, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Student Forum. Includes correspondence with Dean E.R. Riesen, Chairman and information about the First Annual University Circus, 1932, sponsored by the Forum. 1931-1935 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Proposed Veterinary Department. 1928, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Whisky Permit for research purposes. 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Y.M.C.A. 1928-1933 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1928-1936
    - Depression Problems at Universities. 1931-1935 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Complaints. 1928-1936 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Applications for positions. Includes letter from A.L. Kroeber recommending Leslie Spier as a physical anthropologist, July 2, 1931. 1928-1936 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Letters of introduction and recommendation from HLS. 1928-1936 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Letters of introduction and recommendation from HLS. 1928-1936 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Publications received. Includes letter from John P. Clum, September 5, 1931, enclosing booklet. 1928-1936 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Anonymous and Queer" (HLS's classification). (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence regarding Arizona and its Heritage, UA General Bulletin no. 3, April 1, 1936. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Appropriations and Enrollment. Graphs, charts, etc. 1934-1935 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Requests for general and miscellaneous information about UA. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Requests for information about faculty. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 2)